purematters.com 2012-12-07

# Privacy Policy | Pure Matters

### Privacy Policy

**Your privacy is important to us.** It is Pure Matters’ policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our websites. This privacy policy applies to the website (“PureMatters.com”) and all products and services offered by Pure Matters.

### Website Visitors

Pure Matters collects non-personally identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, IP address, and the date and time of each visitor request. Pure Matters’ purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how Pure Matters visitors use the website and tailor offerings accordingly. From time to time, Pure Matters may release non-personally identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

### Gathering of Personally Identifying Information

Certain visitors to Pure Matters’ website choose to interact with Pure Matters in ways that require Pure Matters to gather personally identifying information. The amount and type of information that Pure Matters gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who sign up for the Pure Matters newsletter to provide an email address. **Those who engage in transactions with Pure Matters are asked to provide additional information, including, as necessary, the personal and financial information required to process those transactions.** In each case, Pure Matters collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with Pure Matters. Pure Matters does not disclose personally identifying information other than as described below. Visitors can refuse to supply personally identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

### Use of Collected Information

Pure Matters collects and uses your personal information for the following purposes: 

  * To personalize your user experience: We may use information in the aggregate to understand how our users as a group use the services and resources provided on our website.

  * To improve our website: We continually strive to improve our website offerings based on the information and feedback we receive from you.

  * To improve customer service: Your information helps us to more effectively respond to your customer service requests and support needs.

  * To process transactions: We may use the information you provide about yourself when placing an order only to provide service to that order. We do not share this information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to provide the service.

  * To send periodic emails: The email address you provide for order processing will be used to send information and updates pertaining to your order. It may also be used to respond to your inquiries and/or other requests or questions. If you opt in to our mailing list, you will receive emails that may include company news, updates, related product or service information, etc. If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, we include detailed unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email, or you may contact us via www.purematters.com or at the phone number and address listed below.

### Calculators and Other Tools

Our website contains a number of calculators, quizzes and other tools designed to provide you with information about particular health conditions and help you determine risk factors and potential approaches to managing risk factors that you may want to discuss with your health care provider. The questions and answers to these tools contain potentially sensitive health information. This information may be used to customize your website experience and to recommend appropriate products and services. This information will never be shared with any other party. 

### Aggregated Statistics

Pure Matters may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites. For instance, Pure Matters may monitor the most popular articles viewed or products being sold. Pure Matters may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, Pure Matters does not disclose personally identifying information other than as described below.

### Protection of Certain Personally Identifying Information

Pure Matters will not rent, sell or trade potentially personally identifying and personally identifying information to anyone. Pure Matters discloses potentially personally identifying and personally identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on Pure Matters’ behalf or to provide services available at Pure Matters’ websites, and (ii) have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using Pure Matters’ websites, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. We may use third-party service providers to help us operate our business and the website or administer activities on our behalf, such as sending out newsletters or surveys, shipping products, or processing credit card orders. These companies will not retain, share, store or use any of our users' personal information for any secondary purposes.

Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, Pure Matters discloses potentially personally identifying and personally identifying information only when required to do so by law, or when Pure Matters believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the safety, property or rights of Pure Matters, third parties or the public at large. If you are a registered user of a Pure Matters website and have supplied your email address, Pure Matters may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with Pure Matters and our products. If you send us a request, we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. Pure Matters takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally identifying and personally identifying information.

### Cookies

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Pure Matters uses cookies to help identify and track visitors, their usage of Pure Matters' websites, and their website access preferences. Pure Matters visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using Pure Matters’ websites, with the drawback that certain features of Pure Matters’ websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

### Ads

Ads appearing on our website may be delivered to users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by Pure Matters and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

### third Party Websites

Users may find advertising or other content on our website that links to the sites and services of our partners, suppliers, advertisers, sponsors, licensors and other third parties. We do not control the content or links that appear on these sites and are not responsible for the practices employed by websites linked to or from our site. In addition, these websites or services, including their content and links, may be constantly changing. These websites and services may have their own privacy policies and customer service policies. Browsing and interaction on any other website, including websites that have a link to our site, is subject to that website's own terms and policies.

### Compliance with Children's Online Privacy Protection Act

Pure Matters is not designed to attract anyone under age 13, and we do not knowingly collect identifiable personal information from children under age 13. If we discover that a person under the age of 13 has provided us with any personally identifiable information, we will delete that information from our systems. We are unable to reply to information requests from children under the age of 13, if so identified. A parent or guardian must initiate any requests for information from children under the age of 13 on their behalf. We encourage parents to supervise children when they browse the Internet.

### Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Pure Matters may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in Pure Matters’ sole discretion. Pure Matters encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.

### Contacting Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site or your dealings with this website, please contact us at:

Pure Matters  

Besins Healthcare  
607 Herndon Pkwy  
Suite 210  
Herndon, VA 20170  
800-326-8299
